Jerry Lewis Papers
National Audio-Visual Conservation Center, Library of Congress
- Series 2. Television Scripts and Production Materials, 1960-1970
  - The Jerry Lewis Show, 1967-1969
    - Guild and artist contracts
      - Guest entertainers
        - Roger Williams (Box-folder 57/66)
        - The Young Americans (Box-folder 57/67)
  - Unproduced film and television works, and non-Jerry Lewis productions
    - MPAA title registrations (Box-folder 58/1-2)
    - The Ambushers (Matt Helm film starring Dean Martin), storyboards, 1967 (Box-folder 58/3-4)
    - Gullible's Travels (Box-folder 58/5)
    - He Couldn't Get Mad teleplay-treatment, 1959 (Box-folder 58/6)
    - It's a Small World (Box-folder 58/7)
    - Like Father, Like Son treatments (Box-folder 58/8)
    - Permanent Waves (Box-folder 58/9-10)
    - Punch & Judy (Box-folder 58/11)
- Series 3. Itineraries, 1967-1980
  - Daily itineraries, 1967-1970 (Box 59)
  - Daily itineraries, 1971-1972 (Box 60)
  - Daily itineraries, 1973-1974 (Box 61)
  - Daily itineraries, 1975-1976 (Box 62)
  - Daily itineraries, 1977-1978 (Box 63)
  - Daily itineraries, 1979-1980 (Box 64)
- Series 4. Office Files and Correspondence, 1956-1999
  - Ernie Glucksman files, 1958-1961
    Ernest D. Glucksman was producer or associate producer for multiple Jerry Lewis television appearances and films from 1950-1964.
    - A, 1961 (Box-folder 65/1)
    - ABC, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 65/2)
    - Advertising agencies, 1961 (Box-folder 65/3)
    - B, 1961 (Box-folder 65/4)
    - P. T. Barnum (Box-folder 65/5)
    - Bashful Bullfighter, 1959 (Box-folder 65/6)
    - C, 1961 (Box-folder 65/7)
    - Christmas (Box-folder 65/8)
    - D, 1961 (Box-folder 65/9)
    - Decca (Box-folder 65/10)
    - E, 1961 (Box-folder 65/11)
    - Frank Gorshin, 1961 (Box-folder 65/12)
    - Famous Music (Box-folder 65/13)
    - G, 1961 (Box-folder 65/14)
    - Glucksman, personal, 1961 (Box-folder 65/15)
    - H, 1961 (Box-folder 65/16)
    - K, 1961 (Box-folder 65/17)
    - The Kid Councillor (Box-folder 65/18)
    - L, 1961 (Box-folder 65/19)
    - Letters to and answered for Jerry Lewis, 1961 (Box-folder 66/1)
    - Jerry Lewis Productions, 1961 (Box-folder 66/2)
    - M, 1961 (Box-folder 66/3)
    - Main titles, Ladies Man (Box-folder 66/4)
    - Material file (Box-folder 66/5)
    - Copies of letters not sent to Bill Mazur (Box-folder 66/6)
    - Marvin Meyer (Box-folder 66/7)
    - Muscular Dystrophy, 1958--1961, Jun. (Box-folder 66/8)
    - Muscular Dystrophy, 1961, Jul.-Dec. (Box-folder 66/9)
    - N, 1961 (Box-folder 66/10)
    - NBC (Box-folder 66/11)
    - O-P, 1961 (Box-folder 66/12)
    - Patti Enterprises (Box-folder 66/13)
    - Permanent Waves (Box-folder 66/14)
    - Personal expense account (Box-folder 66/15)
    - Printed forms (Box-folder 66/16)
    - Proctor commercials (Box-folder 66/17)
    - Proctor show, 1960, May 20 (Box-folder 67/1)
    - Projects (Box-folder 67/2)
    - Proposed TV situations (Box-folder 67/3)
    - Publicity (Box-folder 67/4)
    - Q-R, 1961 (Box-folder 67/5)
    - Remember book (Box-folder 67/6)
    - Requests for aid, donations, 1961 (Box-folder 67/7)
    - Requests for benefits and appearances, 1961 (Box-folder 67/8)
    - S, 1961 (Box-folder 67/9)
    - Seidman and Seidman (Box-folder 67/10)
    - Showmanship award (Box-folder 67/11)
    - Signed script release forms (Box-folder 67/12)
    - T, 1961 (Box-folder 67/13)
    - Ticket requests (Box-folder 67/14)
    - Titles, 1961 (Box-folder 67/15)
    - TV appearances (Box-folder 67/16)
    - TV contacts (Box-folder 67/17)
    - TV show layouts, unused lyrics, etc. (Box-folder 67/18)
    - U-V, 1961 (Box-folder 67/19)
    - W, 1961 (Box-folder 67/20)
    - Writers' Guild of America (Box-folder 67/21)
    - X-Z, 1961 (Box-folder 67/22)
  - Office correspondence and memos, 1960-1997
    - Correspondence, 1960, Jan.-Mar. (Box-folder 68/1)
    - The Sands statements, 1960 (Box-folder 68/2)
    - Screen Producers Guild dinner, 1961, Mar. 5 (Box-folder 68/3)
    - Marvin Meyer, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 68/4)
    - Jerry Lewis biographies, 1962-1965, 1970 (Box-folder 68/5)
    - ABC, Chicago, 1963, Mar. 30 (Box-folder 68/6)
    - Ernest D. Glucksman memos, 1963 (Box-folder 68/7)
    - Memos, 1963 (Box-folder 68/8)
    - To-and-fro, 1963 (Box-folder 68/9)
    - Correspondence--In, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 68/10)
    - Correspondence--Out, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 69/1)
    - Interoffice correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 69/2)
    - Correspondence--In, 1965 (Box-folder 69/3)
    - Correspondence--Out, 1965 (Box-folder 69/4)
    - Interoffice correspondence, 1965 (Box-folder 69/5)
    - Personal correspondence, 1965-1969 (Box-folder 69/6)
    - Letters from wife and children, 1969 (Box-folder 69/7)
    - Business correspondence, N, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 69/8)
    - NBC correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 69/9)
    - Jerry Lewis's 50th birthday cards, wires, letters, etc. (MDA Associates), 1976 (Box-folder 69/10)
    - Correspondence with Jack Keller, 1976, Aug. (Box-folder 69/11)
    - Letter from Jerry Lewis to Robert Altman, 1978, Nov. 13 (Box-folder 69/12)
    - Correspondence, 1979 (Box-folder 69/13)
    - Correspondence, 1994 (Box-folder 69/14)
    - Damn Yankees correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 69/15)
    - Correspondence, miscellaneous (Box-folder 69/16)
  - Auricon/16mm literature (Box 112)
  - Guild agreements (Box 70)
  - Laffilms, Inc. (Box 71)
  - MDAA telethon files, 1960s (Box 72)
  - MDAA telethon files, 1970s (Box 73)
  - MDAA telethon talent bios, 1980s (Box 74)
  - Network Cinema (Box 75)
  - Joe Stabile files, 1972-1973 (Box 76)
  - Stereo room, Jerry Lewis, personal (Box 113)
  - USC course (Box 77)
  - York Pictures vs. Jerry Lewis depositions, 1961-1962 (Box 78)
  - York Pictures vs. Jerry Lewis depositions (Box 79)
  - Miscellaneous office files, 1956-1999
    - Acapulco Film Festival, 1967 (Box-folder 80/1)
    - Advertising specialties (Box-folder 80/2)
    - AFTRA (Box-folder 80/3)
    - AGVA, 1960, 1964 (Box-folder 80/4)
    - Australian tour rundowns, 1999 (Box-folder 80/5)
    - Ernest Borgnine (Box-folder 80/6)
    - Branch/theater survey (Box-folder 80/7)
    - Chicago, Woods Theatre premiere, 1960, Nov. (Box-folder 80/8)
    - Yanou Collart, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 80/9-10)
    - Ephemera, 1960s (Box-folder 80/11)
    - Glossary of motion picture terms (Box-folder 80/12)
    - Las vegas material, dupe (Box-folder 80/13)
    - Jerry Lewis's act, script form (the Jerry Lewis show, Sands Hotel, Las Vegas), 1958, Sept. 21 (Box-folder 81/1)
    - Jerry Lewis personal, Christmas material (Box-folder 81/2)
    - Magna Artists Corporation (school concerts) (Box-folder 81/3)
    - Membership cards (Box-folder 81/4)
    - Miscellaneous information pertaining to distribution of product; notes, tearsheets; letters, etc. (Box-folder 81/5)
    - Movieland wax museum (Box-folder 81/6)
    - Newsreel (Box-folder 81/7)
    - "The Only Official Jerry Lewis Fan Club Publication" (Box-folder 81/8)
    - "Ode to My Partner," Jerry Lewis euology for Dean Martin, 1995, Dec. 28 (Box-folder 81/9)
    - Patsy to Nutty, miscellaneous and survey (Box-folder 81/10)
    - Personal appearances, 1956-1958 (Box-folder 81/11)
    - Personal loans (Box-folder 81/12)
    - Phone directory (Box-folder 81/13)
    - Press clipping bureau and fan mail club correspondence (Box-folder 81/14)
    - Props (Box-folder 81/15)
    - Quotations (Box-folder 81/16)
    - "Rock Me, Jerry Lewis" (Box-folder 81/17)
    - Dr. Mitchell Rosenthal, Phoenix House Foundation (Box-folder 81/18)
    - Rubin and Kor, 1990 (Box-folder 81/19)
    - Rudolph Valentino Awards, 1990 (Box-folder 81/20)
    - Sands Hotel, 1964, Oct. 19-31 (Box-folder 81/21)
    - Frank Sennes (Box-folder 81/22)
    - Shipping (Box-folder 81/23)
    - TWA, 1964 (Box-folder 81/24)
    - "Uncle Sam's Billion Dollar Pawn Shop," by Jack Keller (Box-folder 81/25)
    - l'Universe d'une Star (Box-folder 81/26)
    - "Youth Wants to Know", 1959 (Box-folder 81/27)
- Series 5. Press Clippings, 1950s-2011
  - Press clippings, 1950s-1964 (Box 82)
  - Press clippings, 1964-1970 (Box 83)
  - French publicity for Which Way to the Front (Box-folder 127/7-9)
  - Press clippings, 1971, Jan.-Aug. (Box 84)
  - Press clippings, 1971 (Box 85)
  - Press clippings, 1971 (Box 86)
  - Press clippings, 1971-1974 (Box 87)
  - Press clippings, 1975-1977 (Box 88)
  - Press clippings, 1978-1979 (Box 89)
  - Press clippings, 1979 (Box 90)
  - Press clippings, 1979 (Box 91)
  - Press clippings, 1970s-1980 (Box 92)
  - French periodical press for Hardly Working, 1980 (Box 114)
  - Press clippings, 1980-1981 (Box 93)
  - Press clippings, 1981 (Box 94)
  - Press clippings, 1982 (Box 95)
  - Press clippings, 1983-1984 (Box 96)
  - Press clippings, 1984-1986 (Box 97)
  - Press clippings, 1987 (Box 98)
  - Press clippings, 1987-1988 (Box 99)
  - Press clippings, 1988-1989 (Box 100)
  - Press clippings, 1989-1990 (Box 101)
  - Press clippings, 1990-1991 (Box 102)
  - Press clippings, 1992-1996 (Box 103)
  - French periodical press, 1993 (Box 115)
  - Press clippings for Damn Yankees (Box 104)
  - Periodical press for Damn Yankees, 1995-2000 (Box 116)
  - Press clippings, 1996-1998 (Box 105)
  - Press clippings, 1999-2000 (Box 106)
  - Press clippings, 2001-2002 (Box 17)
  - Press clippings, 2002-2004 (Box 108)
  - Press clippings, 2004-2011 (Box 109)
- Series 6. Scrapbooks, 1951-1977
  - Dean Martin and Jerry Lewis [clippings], 1951, Jun.-Dec. (Box 174)
  - Dean Martin and Jerry Lewis [clippings], 1952, May--Oct. (Box 128)
  - Dean Martin and Jerry Lewis [clippings], 1952, Nov.--1953, Feb. (Box 129)
  - [Clippings], 1953, Dec.--1954, Apr. (Box 130)
  - [Clippings], 1955, Nov. 7--1956, Sept. 15 (Box 131)
  - [Clippings], 1956, Jun. 20-25 (Box 132)
  - 4th annual Billboard, Sands, 1956, Oct. 13--1957, Feb. 20 (Box 133)
  - [Clippings], 1956, Oct. 22--1957, Sept. (Box 134)
  - Palace Theatre press, 1956, Dec.--1957, Feb. (Box 135)
  - [Clippings], 1956, Dec.--1957, Jul. (Box 136)
  - Telegrams, 1957 (Box 137)
  - [Clippings], 1957, Jan.-Jul. (Box 175)
  - [Clippings], 1957, Feb. (Box 138)
  - [Clippings and photographs], 1957, Feb. 21--1959, Jul. 15 (Box 176)
  - [Clippings], 1957, Mar. 13--Jun. 29 (Box 139)
  - [Clippings], 1957, Mar. 13--Oct. 8 (Box 140)
  - [Clippings and photographs], 1957, Jul. 17--1958, Apr. (Box 177)
  - [Clippings], 1958, Jan. 20--Apr. 18 (Box 141)
  - [Clippings], 1958, Apr.--Dec. 1961 (Box 142)
  - [Clippings], 1958, May--1959, Feb. 1 (Box 143)
  - [Clippings], 1958, Oct. 1--1959, Feb. 20 (Box 144)
  - Mikoyan, 1959, Jan. 13--Aug. 5 (Box 145)
  - [Clippings], 1959, Jan.--1960, Feb. (Box 178)
  - [Clippings], 1959, May-July (Box 146)
  - [Clippings], 1959, Sept. (Box 147)
  - [Clippings and photographs], 1959, Sept.--1960, Nov. (Box 179)
  - [Cartoon clippings from Saturday Evening Post, etc.] (Box 148)
  - [Clippings], 1960, Mar.-Jun. (Box 180)
  - [Clippings], 1960, Mar.-Jul. (Box 181)
  - [Clippings], 1961, Jan. 6--Nov. 30 (Box 182)
  - [Clippings], 1961, Dec.--1962, Jul. (Box 183)
  - [Clippings and photographs], 1963, Jan.-Dec. (Box 184)
  - [Clippings], 1963, Jun.-Sept. (Box 185)
  - [Clippings], 1963, Dec.--1964, Jul. (Box 186)
  - [Clippings], 1962, Aug.--1963, Jun. (Box 187)
  - [Clippings], 1964, Jan.--Dec. (Box 188)
  - [Clippings], 1965, Jan.-Jul., 1965, Dec.--1966, Dec. (Box 189)
  - press clippings, multiple films, 1965, Jan.--1967, Sept. (Box 190)
  - [Clippings], 1966, Jan.-Aug., 1967, Oct.-Dec. (Box 191)
  - Three On a Couch tour, clippings and photographs, 1966, May-Oct. (Box 192)
  - [Clippings], 1967, Jan.-Aug. (Box 193)
  - [Clippings], 1967, Jun.--1977 (Box 149)
  - [Clippings], 1967, Jul.--1968, Apr. (Box 194)
  - [Clippings], 1968, Jan.--1969, May (Box 195)
  - [Clippings], 1961, Apr., 1967, May--1969, Apr., Produced and directed by Susan E. Katz, 1969. (Box 196)
  - [Clippings], 1967, May-1969, Apr., Produced, directed, and compiled by Susan Elena Katz and father Marshall Katz. (Box 197)
  - [Clippings], 1968-1971, 1971, Oct.--1972, Jul. (Box 198)
  - [Clippings], 1969, Jan.-Dec. (Box 199)
  - Foreign press clippings, ca. 1960s (Box 200)
  - [Clippings], 1970, Jan.--1971, Sept. (Box 201)
  - [Clippings], 1972, Feb.--1974, May (Box 202)
  - [Clippings, including Swedish press], 1972, Apr.-Jul. (Box 203)
  - [Clippings and photographs], 1972, Apr.--1975, Aug. (Box 204)
  - [Clippings], 1973-1974 (Box 150)
  - [Clippings], 1975-1976 (Box 151)
  - Family Jewels proof sheets, 1965, Jan. 15-27 (Box 205)
  - Family Jewels proof sheets, 1965, Jan 28--Feb. 10 (Box 206)
  - Family Jewels proof sheets, 1965, Feb. 10-24 (Box 207)
  - Family Jewels proof sheets, 1965, Feb. 25--Mar. 17 (Box 208)
  - Family Jewels proof sheets, 1965, Mar. 18--Apr. 1 (Box 209)
  - Boeing, Boeing rehearsal proof sheets, 1965, Apr. 22-27 (Box 210)
  - Three On a Couch proof sheets, no. 1, 1965, Sept. 13-21 (Box 211)
  - Three On a Couch proof sheets, no. 2, 1965, Sept. 22--Oct. 4 (Box 212)
  - Three On a Couch proof sheets, 1965, Oct. 7-14 (Box 213)
  - Three On a Couch proof sheets, no. 4, 1965, Oct. 15-24 (Box 214)
  - Three On a Couch proof sheets, no. 5, 1965, Oct. 26--Nov. 3 (Box 215)
  - Three On a Couch proof sheets, no. 6, 1965, Nov. 8-12 (Box 216)
  - Three On a Couch proof sheets, no. 3, 1965, Nov. 8-22 (Box 217)
  - Three On a Couch proof sheets, 1965, Nov. (Box 218)
  - Three On a Couch proof sheets, ca. 1965, Nov. (Box 219)
- Series 7. Visual Materials
  - Production stills for Cinderfella, The Errand Boy, Who's Minding the Store?, Family Jewels, 3 on a Couch, Way Way Out, The Big Mouth, and Hook Line and Sinker, 1959-1969 (Box 152)
  - Production stills for The Errand Boy, 1961, Jul.-Sept. (Box 153)
  - Production stills for The Nutty Professor, 1962, Oct.-Nov. (Box 154)
  - Production stills for The Nutty Professor, 1962, Nov. (Box 155)
  - Production stills for The Nutty Professor, 1962, Dec. (Box 156)
  - Production stills for The Patsy, 1964, Jan.-Feb. (Box 157)
  - Production stills for The Patsy, 1964, Feb.-Mar. (Box 158)
  - Production stills for The Disorderly Orderly, 1964, May-Jul. (Box 159)
  - Production stills for The Disorderly Orderly, 1964, Aug.-Sept. (Box 160)
  - Television production stills, 1963-1966 (Box 161)
  - Television production stills, 1966-1970 (Box 162)
  - Oversize photographs, numbered, ca. 1967-1968 (Box 117)
  - Oversize (intermediate size) photographs, nos. 293-637 (Box 121)
  - Oversize (intermediate size) photographs, nos. 624-689 (Box 122)
  - Oversize (intermediate size) photographs, nos. 687-823 (Box 123)
  - Oversize (intermediate size) photographs, nos. 820-897 (Box 124)
  - Oversize (intermediate size) photographs, nos. 865-1018 (Box 125)
  - Oversize (large size) photographs, nos. 107-164 (Box 163)
  - Oversize (large size) photographs, nos. 168-199 (Box 164)
  - Oversize (large size) photographs, nos. 202-220, 222, 324, 419 (Box 165)
  - Oversize photographs, subject order (Box 118)
  - Oversize (intermediate size) photographs, subject order, B-T (Box 126)
  - Oversize (intermediate size) photographs, subject order, U-X (Box-folder 127/1-2)
  - Oversize (large size) photographs, subject order, A-L (Box 166)
  - Oversize (large size) photographs, subject order, M-Z (Box 167)
  - Photographs, assorted (Box 110-111)
  - Oversize photographs, assorted loose (Box 119)
  - Oversize (intermediate size) photographs, assorted (Box-folder 127/3-6)
  - Oversize (large size) photographs, assorted loose prints (Box 168)
  - Oversize (large size) photographs, assorted proof sheets (Box 169)
  - Oversize (large size) photographs, assorted proof sheets (Box 170)
  - Oversize (large size) photographs, assorted proof sheets (Box 171)
  - Oversize (very large size) photographs, assorted proof sheets, 1960s (Box 220)
  - Jerry Lewis as Whistler's Mother, mounted (Box 120)
  - Oversize (large size) mounted prints, loose (Box 172)
  - Oversize (large size) mounted prints, loose (Box 173)